9175471975

xuqingsally@gmail.com

Summary

With a Master's degree in biostatistics and experience of 1 year of data analysis and modeling in clinical data. Did projects of large interview population-based study, data manipulation, survival analysis, prediction model of psychosis and machine learning. I am familiar with SAS and R and very interested in clinical data and wish to contribute to research and decision making in healthcare.

Skills

- SAS (Base and Advanced Programmer Certifications, SAS macro)
- R (R shiny, R markdown)
- SQL
- SPSS
- Tableau
- Excel

Work Experience

Biostatistics Research Assistant

Columbia University/New York State Psychiatric Institute, New York, NY

Jun, 2018 - Present

- Conduct propensity score matching, survival analysis and logistics regression, including building cox survival models, plot survival functions and hazard curves with R, SAS SQL and SAS macro
- Machine Learning for schizophrenia prediction using random forest, boosting and regression models
- Help with data cleaning and make codebook for a large survey database with SAS, SPSS and Excel
- Collaborate with biostatistician and medical researchers for clinical trial data analysis in heart failure and mental health

Research Biostatistician Intern

New York-Presbyterian Hospital, New York, NY

May, 2018 - Aug, 2018

- Explored clinical trial data of trauma among hospitals in New York by using surveys, generalized linear models, cross correlation analysis, longitudinal data analysis, ANOVA and mapping in R
- Collaborated and consulted with surgeons and biostatisticians by contributing to the statistical design, analysis of clinical trials, and other study designs to execute trauma clinical research
- Provided analytic support for clinical and regulatory reports and research papers
- Attended routine meetings for exploring and developing latest clinical designs

Data Analyst Intern

Mobile MD System, Zhejiang, China

Jun, 2016 - Aug, 2016

- Worked on database maintenance clinical/health data organization, classification, clearing, entry, etc
- Collaborated with data scientists and biostatisticians to elicit data, build proper designs, perform statistical analysis with SAS and interpret results to clients

Education

Master of Science: Biostatistics

Columbia University, Mailman School of Public Health

New York, NY, May, 2019

Courses: Probability, Biostatistics methods, Statistical Inference, Data Science, Epidemiology, Survival Analysis, Analysis of Longitudinal, Design of Medical Experiment, Bayesian Analysis, Randomized Clinical Trial GPA: 3.77

Bachelor of Science: Biological Science

Nanjing University

GPA: 3.76

Nanjing, China, Jun, 2017